Guide to the Martin, Mary Hetty Bonar Papers 1863-1918
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Martin, Mary Hetty Bonar Papers
1863-1918
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 242
Martin, Mary Hetty Bonar
1 container. .5 linear feet of shelf space.
Diaries, 1885-1918, of farm life in Entiat Valley; clippings and other papers; also portrait and ledger of her father, James Crayton Bonar, 1829-1892.
Diaries, 1885-1918, of farm life in Entiat Valley; clippings and other papers; also portrait and ledger of her father, James Crayton Bonar, 1829-1892.
This collection is open for research use.
The papers of Mary Bonar Martin, b. 1860, were a gift of John Brown in 1970.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Martin, Mary Hetty Bonar, 1860- --Archives; Bonar, James Crayton, 1829-1892; Brown, John. waps
Frontier and pioneer life--Washington (State)--Entiat River Valley--Sources
Diaries; Pioneers; Washington (State)
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Series 1: Mary Martin Hetty Bonar Papers, 1885-1918
  - Diary, June 14, 1885-August 25, 1885 (Folder 1)
  - Diaries, 1878-1902 (Folder 2)
  - Diaries, 1903-1904 (Folder 3)
  - Diaries, March 4, 1904-August 3, 1907 (Folder 4)
  - Diaries, August 4, 1907-November 23, 1910 (Folder 5)
  - Diaries, December 24, 1910-January 1914 (Folder 6)
  - Diaries, January 1914-August 1918 (Folder 7)
  - Notes on Entiat history, Walker family; clippings re: Wenatchee history and Bonar-Martin marriage (Folder 8)
- Series 2: James Crayton Bonar Papers, 1863-1892
  - Portrait of J. C. Bonar, Forest City, Iowa, 1868; Tintype 18 x 13 cm (Folder 9)
  - Ledger. Contains justice court records, family records, legal documents, clippings, accounts and diary entries, 1863-1892; 1 volume. (Folder 10)
  - Donor correspondence and typescript transcriptions of items 1 and 10, 1970 (Folder 11)